

WEB3 RESEARCHER & DATA SCIENTIST

■ he.mingxuan527@gmail.com | ★ mingxuanhe.xyz | ● @MingXDynasty

Profile

I am a crypto-native quantitative researcher and data scientist with rigorous academic and project experiences across TradFi and Web3. My greatest strength is the ability to make sense of complex algebraic formulas and big data then transform them into valuable, human-readable information through written and oral reports. My interest lies broadly in DeFi and tokenomics.

Core skills: quantitative research, machine learning, computational simulation, onchain analytics, technical writing

Education ___

University of Chicago Chicago

M.A. IN COMPUTATIONAL SOCIAL SCIENCE - ECONOMICS

Aug 2022 - May 2024

Aug 2018 - May 2022

• Advisor: Dr. Gina Pieters

• Thesis: Dynamic Modeling for Optimal Cryptoeconomic Policies

Grinnell College Grinnell, IA

B.A. IN MATHEMATICS AND B.A. IN ECONOMICS WITH HONORS

• Advisors: Dr. Jennifer Pauhlus, Dr. Keith Brouhle

Experiences ____

RESEARCH & DATA SCIENCE INTERN

Jun 2023 - Sep 2023

Worked with Nethermind's research team on open-ended / on-demand research projects related to DeFi and cryptoeconomics

- · LSD Modeling: Developed an agent-based modeling & simulation framework for liquid staking protocols
- Lido Validators: Researched and co-developed mechanisms against white-labels in Lido's validator network; designed architecture for a zero-knowledge machine learning (zkML) classifier model to detect white-labels
- Institutional Research: Produced data-driven research reports on emerging DeFi topics for a top-tier institutional client

Polygon

RESEARCH ANALYST (DEFI)

Oct 2022 - Jun 2023

• Conducted deep-dive analyses for over 20 decentralized perpetual futures (perp) exchanges; studied protocols' technical and economic aspects including risk profiles and detailed collateral, liquidity, and funding mechanisms and synthesized them into internal documentation.

ELBICA Lab

Undergraduate Researcher

Jun 2021 – Sep 2021

• Led a group of three students to study evolutionary game theory on complex networks; designed and developed multi-agent machine learning systems in *Python* using *networkx*; conducted experiments on various network topologies and model parameters; compiled, analyzed, and visualized experiment data

Research Papers __

WORKING PAPERS

He, M. (WIP) Dynamic Modeling for Optimal Cryptoeconomic Policies.

PUBLISHED PAPERS

He, M., Gao, M., Gao, Y., & Eliott, F. M. (2022). Cascading Failures and the Robustness of Cooperation in a Unified Scale-Free Network Model. In *Complex Networks & Their Applications X*, 2022. Springer, Cham. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-030-93413-2_31

SHORT PAPERS AND RESEARCH REPORTS

Short papers and research reports are available here: https://mingxuanhe.xyz/projects

Research blogs and threads are available here: https://mingxuanhe.xyz/writings

Presentations _____

- **He, M.** (2023) Post-Shanghai Liquid Staking Derivatives and Bank Run Risks. Science of Blockchain Conference (SBC) Decentralized Financial Stability Forum, Stanford University, Palo Alto, U.S.
- He, M. (2023) Post-Shanghai Liquid Staking Derivatives and Bank Run Risks. ETHChicago, Chicago, U.S..
- **He, M.** (2023) Workshop on Agent-Based Simulations for Protocol Design, Tokenomics, and Risk Analysis. ETHChicago, Chicago, U.S..
- **He, M.**, Gao, M., Gao, Y., & Eliott, F. M. (2021). Cascading Failures and the Robustness of Cooperation in a Unified Scale-Free Network Model. International Conference on Complex Networks and their Applications (ICCNA21), Polytechnic University of Madrid, Madrid, Spain.

Professional Services

Uniswap Foundation

FOUNDING MEMBER, MEV+UX WORKING GROUP

Oct 2023 — Present

- Invited as a founding member of new research group working on solutions to UX issues related to DeFi MEV
- Collaborated with researchers from multiple disciplines to foster theoretical and data-driven approaches to MEV challenges

ETHChicago Chicago, IL, U.S.
COMMUNITY CO-ORGANIZER Sep 2023

- Facilitated organization of the inaugural event through professional outreach and network collaborations
- Gave a presentation and hosted an hour-long hackathon workshop aimed at upskilling hackathon participants

Grants and Awards

2023	Gitcoin Grants 18, Gitcoin & Token Engineering Commons	\$ 3,500
2023	Nethermind Internship Stipend, Ethereum Foundation Ecosystem Support Program	\$ 3,000
2022, 2023	Phoenix Graduate Merit Scholarship, University of Chicago	\$ 52,000
2021	MAP Research Grant, Grinnell College	\$ 3,000

Teaching Experiences _____

- 2022 Onchain data analytics mentor / judge, Blockbeam DeFi Bootcamp
- 2021 Intermediate microeconomics mentor, Grinnell College
- 2018-2021 Co-founder and SAT tutor, Peer Insight Education

Languages and Tools _____

Computing languages: Python, Matlab, Stata, SQL, Julia, LaTeX

Libraries: numpy, pandas, scipy, sklearn, statsmodels, xgboost, matplotlib, seaborn, plotly, mesa, networkx, sympy, spark, dask, flask, solara

Platforms & tools: Git/Github, Dune, Flipside, AWS, Conda, Google Colab, Heroku, MPI, OpenCL

Natural languages: Mandarin (native), English (fluent), French (beginner)